# **ASHIM RAJ SHRESTHA**

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



https://github.com/ashimxtha4

ashim.xtha2000@gmail.com



https://portfolio-jecb-git-masterashimxtha4.vercel.app/



9841010721

#### SUMMARY

Motivated and results-driven frontend-heavy Software Engineer with nearly 2 years of experience. Front-End Developer with thirst for knowledge and advancement. Need to try new things and accept new challenges. Good at finding loopholes and nifty solutions to make things work. Open minded to any solution and different ways and practices.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Kodiary Technologies**

**Software Developer** • February 2024 - Currently

- Create dynamic maps and features related to maps.
- Communicate with client for proper flow of work and requirement and feature management.
- Create and maintain proper code base and system for optimized reusable and sustainable code.
- Take the project till deployment and maintain with critical bug fixing and problem solving

#### Freelance

Software Developer • July 2023 - March 2024

- Create dynamic forms according to backend data and patient
- Provide proper hierarchy for users and admin and access.
- Create dynamic components with dynamic tables to display survey data of different cases and samples.
- Communicate with backend and guide interns in minor capacity

#### Asterdio Inc.

Software Developer • May 2022 - August 2023

- Create dynamic and responsible web application with respect to design.
- Expertise in React js and Next js and creating precise UI and problem solving requiring calculation of data from different components.
- Expanded skills into backend development using Node and Python.
- Proficient in TypeScript to enhance code structure and static typing.
- Develop and execute unit tests and perform system testing to ensure software quality
- Implemented proper flow of product and use best practice and manage state for all features and made dynamic pages with different level of authorization.
- Contributed to the design efficient software that looks good and works without extra byproduct.
- Collaborate with team to insure proper flow of information and work and conduct end of day meets.

Software Developer Intern • February 2022 - May 2022

- Understanding flow and working of front-end technology like React.js and Next.js
- Collaborated with the back-end team to improve the data provided from backend.
- Troubleshot and resolved bugs and issues.

#### SKILLS

- Programming Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript
- Backend Technologies: Node.js, Django
- Frontend Technologies: React.js, Next.js, Vue., Nuxt
- Databases: MongoDB and SQL
- Version Control: Git
- Problem Solving and Debugging
- RESTful API
- Software Architecture and Design Patterns
- Performance Optimization
- Unit Testing

## **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor in Computer Science and** Engineering

Sree Vidyanikethan Eiginnering College • 2019-2022

+2 Science

D.A.V • 2016-2018

#### PROJECTS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Basobaas -[Test redesign project]
- Basobaas Blog-[Redesign]
- Agrobase Nepal -[Live]
- Auto 24 [Live-Multiple Language]
- AutoBevy [UAT]
- SIDDAX [UAT, Going Live soon]-Freelance
- Cronlink-[UAT for some feature and some feature in dev]-Kodiary
- Jhyappi bulk SMS [Live]-Kodiary
- Justnotarize [UAT,Going Live soon]-Kodiary